### Mohammad El Prince

Mississauga, ON | 519-760-1559 | mohammad-elprince@proton.me LinkedIn | Github | Portfolio

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

Full Stack Software Engineer with experience in JavaScript and Python-based programming. With a background in mechanical engineering and operations, I have a can-do attitude and bring strong skills in problem-solving, communication, and collaboration. I have a clear vision for leveraging technology to solve complex challenges and create meaningful impact. As a lifelong learner, I am committed to growing my technical knowledge and leadership skills. I enjoy tackling challenges head-on and crafting creative solutions to real-world problems. My belief in the power of teamwork through the Agile methodology guides me in achieving exceptional results.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, React.js, Next.js, FastAPI, Scss, SQL, VSCode, Git

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

#### WriteWell - GitHub | Demo | Live

WriteWell is a full-stack app that enables bloggers to share, edit, and delete blogs.

- Built with Next.js end-to-end and styled with Scss.
- Employed Next.is routing ability to construct endpoints for API requests.
- Utilized MySQL as the database, which is deployed on AWS RDS.
- Deployed images to AWS S3 and linked them to the database.

#### Portfolio - GitHub | Demo | Live

A high-quality digital showcase of my professional journey, highlighting my skills and projects.

- Employed HTML, CSS, and JavaScript showcasing my abilities to learn and in front-end web development and design.
- Incorporated interactive elements and animation using JS and CSS.
- Maintained DRY coding following best practices in all the project files.

#### GPT-3 Intro - GitHub | Demo | Live

A landing page created to describe GPT-3 technology that provides a brief introduction about this modern AI technology.

- Built with ReactJS and CSS styling showcasing an appealing user experience.
- Incorporated BEM (Block Element Modifier) technique to relate JSX elements to styling and for consistency.
- Deployed JSON server as the backend server.

#### Budget Tracker CLI - GitHub | Demo

A command-line application designed to help you manage your finances and track your expenses easily.

- Coded python scripts and functions and maintained DRY coding.
- Imported SQLAlchemy for database management.
- Implemented the rich library for a user-friendly CL interface.

EDUCATION	
Flatiron School Full Stack Web Development, Python and JavaScript online program	02/2023 - 10/2023
University of Guelph, Guelph, ON Master of Engineering — Mechanical Engineering (course-based)	01/2019 – 02/2021
King Fahd University of Petroleum and Minerals, Dhahran, KSA Master of Science — Mechanical Engineering (Thesis-based) Bachelor of Science — Mechanical Engineering (course-based)	09/2016 - 12/2018 01/2012 - 05/2016

#### RECENT PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Amazon, Hamilton/St. Thomas/London/Mississauga, ON

05/2021 - Present

- Lead Fulfillment Associate/Field Quality Assurance
  - Manage 50+ Associates across Amazon Robotics (AR) floor and inventory workstations.
  - Monitor the health of four Amazon Robotics floors for optimal productivity and safe operation.
  - Guide Associate for an optimized performance resulting in 10% improvement in the AR floor health.
  - Train Level1 Leads and provide coverage for other managers of operation.
  - Identify barriers to first-time delivery success; recommend improvements to Amazon's systems and processes.
  - Interact with property managers regarding deliveries and address concerns with service levels being provided.

# **University of Guelph,** Guelph, ON Research/Teaching Assistant

01/2019 - 05/2021

- Lectured large groups of students (75 150 students) on fundamental engineering courses and proctored exams.
- Conducted experimental and theoretical research in the area of safety of nuclear power plants.
- Provided coverage for professors in lectures.
- Designed assessments and graded students' reports, video reports, assignments, exams, and classroom activities.

## King Fahd University of Petroleum and Minerals, Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

09/2016 - 12/2018

- Teaching/Research Assistant
- Authored two scientific journal papers developing novel studies that improved studies of other authors.
- Developed a computational study that improved the prediction of the gas well lifetime partnering with Saudi Aramco.
- Provided coverage for professors in lectures.
- Graded students' reports, assignments, exams, and classroom activities.
- Lectured fundamental mechanical engineering labs and courses over the course of 5 semesters.